Guide to the Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games, 1972-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games 1972-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Murray, Edwin, and Terry Murray (collectors)
250 linear feet Extent: Approx. 13,000 Items
Edwin L. and Terry A. Murray, brothers residing in Durham, North Carolina, have been collectors of comic books and other pulp culture for forty years. Collection includes role-playing game boxed sets, miniatures, card sets, role-play game magazines and literature, campaign guides, modules, and rule books.
RL.00924
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, drop-in game play is not possible with this collection. Please contact Special Collections with questions about the appropriate use of this material.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Edwin and Terry Murray Collection of Role-Playing Games was received by the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library as a gift in 2002, 2010, and 2012.
Historical Note
Table-top role-playing games (RPGs) are a type of game where players create or assume the role of various characters and collaborate to imagine and build a story or quest. Each players' characterization offers guidelines and expectations for the abilities and tendencies of their character, and their proposed actions succeed or fail based on the game's established rules and statistics. One player may serve as a gamemaster to guide fellow players through the game and introduce new challenges or twists to the story.
Modern role-playing games emerged in the 1970s, with the first commercially available game, Dungeons & Dragons, published in 1974. It quickly became very popular, leading to copycats and competitors as well as enabling the development of RPG supporting material, such as campaign sets, miniatures and playing pieces, new literature, and fan magazines. Other popular games quickly followed, such as Advanced Dungeons and Dragons in 1977, Traveller in 1977, RuneQuest in 1978, Call of Cthulhu in 1981, and James Bond in 1983.
RPGs continued to grow and evolved through the late 1980s and 1990s. General game systems emerged, allowing for a single set of rules that worked with any setting. Another notable milestone was the release of Magic: The Gathering in 1993, which proved very popular and resulted in more spin-offs and competition in the field of collectible card games. Early computer games frequently adopted or mimicked RPG rules, eliminating the need for a gamemaster and increasing the game's speed. Many contemporary video games share their terminology, settings, and game mechanics with pen-and-paper RPGs.
Collection Overview
This collection includes thousands of game books, boxed sets, figurines, cards, magazines and serials. It also includes a small amount of manuscript material from the Murrays' own campaign notes and records. The materials have been divided into series based on format: Boxed Games (BG); Modules, Manuals, and Campaign Volumes (M); Miniatures and Pieces (P); Cards (C); Serials (S); and Manuscripts (MS). Within each series, materials have been sorted into their various game worlds and settings as best as possible. Along with Box and Volume numbers, barcodes for each item are included to ease research requests from Duke's offsite storage facility. Due to the vast number of games and the wide variety of research interests for this collection, a downloadable spreadsheet is available for researchers interested in browsing and sorting the games in different ways, such as by year or by box.
Download RPG spreadsheet
Please note: The collection contains loose parts such as dice, tokens, figurines, cards, etc. Some materials may be sealed in original packaging. Packaged materials in Miniatures series are intended to remain in sealed packaging. Please consult Research Services staff for assistance with removal of other materials from sealed packaging. Please return materials to original packaging whenever possible. Consult Research Services staff for assistance if materials cannot be returned to original packaging.
The Boxed Games (BG) series includes games from a range of worlds, as well as a large number of general games that date from the early 1970s to the mid-2000s. Large sub-series within the Boxed Games series include game settings and worlds like Dungeons & Dragons, Forgotten Realms, James Bond, DragonLance, RuneQuest, Star Trek, and Supremacy; but, there are many more from a large number of different systems. Boxed Games typically include campaign books and characterization sheets, grids or maps for game play, die, and rule books.
The Modules, Manuals, and Campaign Volumes (M) series is the largest series in the collection, with over 2300 distinct volumes from numerous game worlds and settings. The series includes a variety of publications, ranging from traditional modules with a plot and characters included, to manuals with lists of creatures or characters, to reference guides for various game worlds. Many companies published only volumes, with no accompanying boxed game, and so there are a large number of titles that have no correlation to the Boxed Games series. The largest game worlds or settings represented in this series are Advanced Dungeons & Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, Cyberpunk, Dungeons & Dragons, Forgotten Realms, Middle-Earth, and Traveller; but, there are many, many more from different game worlds as well as independent, one-time games.
The Miniatures and Pieces (P) series includes packaged and loose miniatures collected by the Murrays from a number of different companies. Most are generic and not attached to a particular game or game brand, although there are hundreds that were intended for playing with games like Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, DC or Marvel Superheroes, or Lord of the Rings. Along with metal miniatures, the series also includes other various types of gameplay aids, including settings guides, grids, and miscellany. A portion of this series consists of unpackaged, handpainted miniatures that have been specially housed for preservation.
The Serials (S) series contains fanzines and magazines collected by the Murrays relating to RPGs and RPG culture. Most magazine runs are incomplete and date from the late 1970s to the mid-2000s; the boxlist includes details about which issues are present in the collection.
The Cards (C) series includes cards from several years of Magic: The Gathering, as well as smaller amounts of cards of other games such as Legend of the Five Rings, New Aeon, Sim City, Spellfire, On the Edge, and Jyhad.
The Manuscripts (MS) series is the smallest series in the collection, containing campaign and collecting notes from the Murrays.
Subject Headings
Murray, Edwin L.; Murray, Terry A., 1953-; DC Comics, Inc.; Marvel Comics Group; Dungeons and Dragons (Game); Call of Cthulhu (Game); Forgotten realms.; Birthright books.; Ars Magica (Game); Battletech.; Buck Rogers in the 25th century.; Castle Falkenstein (Game); Cyberpunk.; Dark conspiracy.; Dragonlance.; Earthdawn (Game); Greyhawk.; Indiana Jones.; Middle-Earth (Game); Lord of the Rings (Game); Ravenloft (Game); RuneQuest (Game); Star Trek: The Role Playing Game (Game); Magic: The Gathering (Game); d20 modern (Game); Chill (Game); Traveller (Game); Fantasy games
Description of Collection
- Boxed Games, 1972-2007 and undated, (76 boxes)
  Series includes 448 boxed game sets for role-playing games like Dungeons and Dragons, Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, Call of Cthulhu, Al-Qadim, Car Wars, Traveller, James Bond, and Star Trek. A boxed set typically includes maps and grids, character guides, encounter playbooks, a die, and other literature to be used for creating new or altered worlds within a particular game.
  Contents have been listed alphabetically by game world or campaign, and within each world, chronologically by date. General games that have no identifiable "world" are listed at the end in alphabetical order. Barcodes are included with each title to better assist box requests from off-site. A downloadable spreadsheet is available for researchers who are interested in sorting or browsing the games in a different way.
  - Ace of Aces
    - Ace of Aces. Published by Nova Game Designs, Inc., 1980., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - Ace of Aces. Published by Nova Game Designs, Inc., 1981., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - Ace of Aces: Wingleader. Published by Nova Game Designs, Inc., 1988., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
  - Advanced Dungeons and Dragons
    - Battle System: Fantasy Combat Supplement. Published by TSR, Inc., 1985., D02340858U (Box BG 71)
    - Bloodstone Pass. Published by TSR, Inc., 1985., D02340836Q (Box BG 40)
    - Castles: A 3-Dimensional Game Accessory. Published by TSR, Inc., 1990., D02340858U (Box BG 71)
    - Dragon Mountain. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D02340858U (Box BG 71)
    - Council of Wyrms. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D02340858U (Box BG 71)
    - Fritz Leiber's Lankhmar. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
  - Advanced Dungeons and Dragons, 2nd Edition
    - Monstrous Compendium: Volume One. Published by TSR, Inc., 1989., D02482593X (Box BG 32)
    - Deck of Priest Spells. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D02482594Y (Box BG 33)
    - Wizard Spell Cards. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D02482589 (Box BG 28)
  - Al-Qadim
    - Golden Voyages. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Land of Fate. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - A Dozen and One Adventures. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Assassin Mountain. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - City of Delights. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Secrets of the Lamp. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Caravans. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Cities of Bone. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Corsaurs of the Great Sea. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Runed Kingdoms. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
  - BattleTech
    - BattleTech: A Game of Armored Combat. Published by FASA Corporation, 1985., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - AeroTech: The BattleTech Game of Fighter Combat. Published by FASA Corporation, 1986., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - BattleForce: Small Unit Actions in the 31st Century. Published by FASA Corporation, 1987., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - BattleTroops: A Game of Urban Man-to-Man Combat in the BattleTech Universe. Published by FASA Corporation, 1989., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - BattleTech: A Game of Armored Combat. Published by FASA Corporation, 1992., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - Powerhits BattleTech. Published by Activision, 1992., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - BattleTech Reinforcements 2: Additional Units for BattleTech. Published by FASA Corporation, 1992?., D02340870O (Box BG 60)
    - Battledroids: A Game of Armored Combat. Published by FASA Corporation, undated., D04405971U (Box BG 76)
  - Birthright (Advanced Dungeons and Dragons)
    - Birthright: Campaign Setting. Published by TSR, Inc., 1995., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
    - Birthright: Cities of the Sun. Published by TSR, Inc., 1995., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
    - Birthright: Havens of the Great Bay. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
    - Birthright: The Rjurik Highlands. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
  - Boot Hill
    - Boot Hill: 3rd Edition Wild West Role-Playing Game. Published by TSR, Inc., 1974., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
    - Boot Hill: Role-Playing Game of the West. Published by TSR, Inc., 1979., D02482570S (Box BG 9)
  - Call of Cthulhu
    - Call of Cthulhu: Fantasy Role-Playing in the Worlds of H.P. Lovecraft. Published by Chaosium Inc., 1981., D02340873R (Box BG 62)
    - Masks of Nyarlathotep. Published by Chaosium Inc., 1984., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Cthulhu by Gaslight (1890s). Published by Chaosium Inc., 1986., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Spawn at Azathoth (1920s). Published by Chaosium Inc., 1986., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Horror on the Orient Express (1920s). Published by Chaosium Inc., 1991., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
  - Car Wars
    - Car Wars. Published by Steve Jackson Games, 1985., D02340871P (Box BG 61)
    - Boat Wars: Boats, Aquabikes, Hovercraft and More!. Published by Steve Jackson Games, 1988., D02340871P (Box BG 61)
    - Aeroduel: Aerial Combat in the 21st Century. Published by Steve Jackson Games, 1990., D02340871P (Box BG 61)
    - Tanks: Military Vehicles for the Battlefields of the Future. Published by Steve Jackson Games, 1990., D02340871P (Box BG 61)
    - Car Wars: The Card Game. Published by Steve Jackson Games, undated., D02340871P (Box BG 61)
  - Challenger Series (Dungeons and Dragons)
    - Wrath of the Immortals. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Champions of Mystara: Heroes of the Princess Ark. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
  - Conan
    - Conan. Published by TSR, Inc., 1985., D02340852O (Box BG 55)
    - Messanyia - City of Riches. Published by Mongoose Publishing, 2003., D04405971U (Box BG 76)
    - Shadizar - City of Wickedness. Published by Mongoose Publishing, 2003., D04405971U (Box BG 76)
  - Cyberpunk
    - Cyberpunk: The Roleplaying Game of the Dark Future. Published by R. Talsorian Games Inc., 1980., D02482584X (Box BG 23)
    - Land of the Free: Cyberpunk. Published by R. Talsorian Games Inc., 1994., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
  - Dark Sun (Advanced Dungeons and Dragons)
    - Dark Sun: Face the Fire of the Dark Sun. Published by TSR, Inc., 1991., D02340859V (Box BG 69)
    - The Ivory Triangle. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D02340859V (Box BG 69)
    - City by the Silt Sea. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D02340859V (Box BG 69)
    - Dark Sun. Published by TSR, Inc., 1995., D02340859V (Box BG 69)
    - Mind Lords of the Last Sea. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02340859V (Box BG 69)
  - DC Comics
    - DC Heroes: Role Playing Game Featuring the New Teen Titans. Published by, 1985., D02482572U (Box BG 11)
  - Doctor Who
    - The Doctor Who: Role Playing Game. Published by FASA Corporation, 1985., D02482572U (Box BG 11)
  - DragonLance (Advanced Dungeons and Dragons)
    - Fifth Age. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - Heroes of Steel. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - The Last Tower: The Legacy of Raistlin. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - Heroes of Defiance. Published by TSR, Inc., 1997., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - Heroes of Sorcery. Published by TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast), 1997., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - Citadel of Light. Published by TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast), 1998., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - Wings of Fury. Published by TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast), 1998., D02484475Y (Box BG 70)
    - DragonLance: Monstrous Comendium: Appendix. Published by TSR, Inc., 1989., D02482591V (Box BG 30)
    - Tales of the Lance. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D02340857T (Box BG 67)
    - Dwarven Kingdoms of Krynn. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D02340857T (Box BG 67)
    - Heroes of Hope. Published by TSR, Inc. (Wizards of the Coast), 1997., D02340858U (Box BG 71)
  - DragonQuest
    - DragonQuest: An Experience in Heroic Adventures. Published by Simulations Publications, Inc., 1980., D02482575X (Box BG 14)
    - DragonQuest: An Experience in Heroic Adventures: Great New Second Edition Master Set. Published by Simulations Publications, Inc., 1981., D02482575X (Box BG 14)
  - Dungeonquest
    - Dungeonquest. Published by Games Workshop, 1987., D02482568Z (Box BG 7)
    - Dungeonquest: Catacombs. Published by Games Workshop, 1987., D02482568Z (Box BG 7)
    - Heros for Dungeonquest. Published by Games Workshop, 1987., D02482568Z (Box BG 7)
  - Dungeons & Dragons
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1977., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1980., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1983., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1983., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1984., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1985., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons: Hollow World. Published by TSR, Inc., 1990., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
    - Dungeons & Dragons. Published by TSR, Inc., 1974-1979., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
  - Earthdawn
    - Earthdawn: Barsaive. Published by FASA Corporation, 1993., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
    - Earthdawn: Parlainth: The Forgotten City. Published by FASA Corporation, 1994., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
    - Earthdawn: Sky Point & Vivane. Published by FASA Corporation, 1995., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
  - Elfquest
    - Elfquest: The Official Roleplaying Game. Published by Chaosium Inc., 1984., D02340873R (Box BG 62)
  - Forgotten Realms (Advanced Dungeons and Dragons)
    - Campaign Set. Published by TSR, Inc., 1987., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - City System. Published by TSR, Inc., 1988., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Kara-Tur: The Eastern Realms. Published by TSR, Inc., 1988., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Cities of Mystery. Published by TSR, Inc., 1989., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - The Horde: Barbarian Campaign Setting. Published by TSR, Inc., 1990., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Maztica. Published by TSR, Inc., 1991., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - The Ruins of Undermountain. Published by TSR, Inc., 1991., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Menzoberranzan. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Forgotten Realms Campaign Setting. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D02340872Q (Box BG 68)
    - Campaign Setting. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993/1994., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - The Ruins of Myth Drannor. Published by TSR, Inc., 1993., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - City of Splendors. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - Elminster's Ecologies. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
    - The Ruins of Undermountain II. Published by TSR, Inc., 1994., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Spellbound. Published by TSR, Inc., 1995., D02484473W (Box BG 72)
    - The Ruins of Zhentil Keep. Published by TSR, Inc., 1995., D02484473W (Box BG 72)
    - Netheril: Empire of Magic. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - The North: Guide to the Savage Frontier. Published by TSR, Inc., 1996., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Lands of Intrigue. Published by TSR, Inc., 1997., D03774871. (Box BG 3)
    - Empress of the Shining Sea. Published by TSR, Inc., 1998., D03774870- (Box BG 2)
  - Gamma World
    - Gamma World. Published by TSR, Inc., 1978., D02482574W (Box BG 13)
    - Gamma World. Published by TSR, Inc., 1983., D02482574W (Box BG 13)
    - Gamma World. Published by TSR, Inc., 1986., D02482574W (Box BG 13)
  - Gangbusters
    - Gangbusters: 1920's Role-Playing Adventure Game. Published by TSR, Inc., 1980., D02482577Z (Box BG 16)
    - Gangbusters: 1920's Role-Playing Adventure Game New 3rd Edition. Published by TSR, Inc., 1982., D02482577Z (Box BG 16)
  - Gazetteer
    - Dawn of the Emperors: Thyatis and Alphatia. Published by TSR, Inc., 1989., D02340908Q (Box BG 66)
  - Ghostbusters
    - Ghostbusters: A Frightfully Cheerful Roleplaying Game. Published by West End Games, Inc., 1986., D02482580T (Box BG 19)
    - Ghostbusters: International: The Humorous Horror Roleplaying Game. Published by West End Games, Inc., 1989., D02482580T (Box BG 19)
  - Greyhawk (Advanced Dungeons and Dragons)
    - World of Greyhawk. Published by TSR, Inc., 1983., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
    - The City of Greyhawk. Published by TSR, Inc., 1989., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
    - Wars. Published by TSR, Inc., 1991., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
    - From the Ashes. Published by TSR, Inc., 1992., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
    - World of Greyhawk. Published by TSR, Inc., 1980., D03774872 (Box BG 4)
  - James Bond
    - James Bond 007: Live and Let Die: An Action Episode Game. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1985., D02340855R (Box BG 58)
    - James Bond 007: Goldfinger: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1983., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: Octopussy: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1983., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service: Gamemaster Pack. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1983., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: The Complete Basic Set: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1983., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
    - James Bond 007: Dr. No: Role Playing in Her Majest's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1984., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: For Your Information: Gamemaster Supplement: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1984., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
    - James Bond 007: Live and Let Die: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1984., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: You Only Live Twice: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1984., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: A View to A Kill: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1985., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: Goldfinger II: The Man with the Midas Touch: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1985., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: The Man with the Golden Gun: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1985., D02340844P (Box BG 48)
    - James Bond 007: Villians: Role Playing in Her Majesty's Secret Service. Published by Victory Games, Inc., 1986., D02340845Q (Box BG 49)
  - Jovian Chronicles
    - Jovian Fleet Blueprint File for Jovian Chronicles. Published by DreamPod 9, Inc., 1998., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
    - Cega Fleet Blueprint File for Jovian Chronicles. Published by DreamPod 9, Inc., 1999., D037748691 (Box BG 1)
  - Judge Dredd
    - Judge Dredd: The Game of Crime-Fighting in Mega-City One. Published by Games Workshop, 1982., D02482569- (Box BG 8)
    - Judge Dredd: The Role-Playing Game. Published by Games Workshop, 1985., D02482569- (Box BG 8)
  - Legend of the Five Rings
    - Legend of the Five Rings: City of Lies. Published by Alderac Entertainment Group, 1996., D02340838S (Box BG 42)
    - The Battle of Beiden Pass. Published by Five Rings Publishing Group Inc, 1996., D02340873R (Box BG 62)
    - Legend of the Five Rings: The Tomb of Iuchiban. Published by Alderac Entertainment Group, undated., D02340838S (Box BG 42)
  - Lord of the Rings
    - Middle Earth: War of the Ring: S.R. 1418 to 1419: based on J.R.R. Tolkien's The Ring Trilogy. Published by Simulations Publications, Inc., 1977., D02340833N (Box BG 37)
    - The Fellowship of the Ring: Based on the works of J.R.R. Tolkien. Published by Iron Crown Enterprises, Inc., 1983., D02340843O (Box BG 47)
  - Lords of Creation
    - Lords of Creation. Published by The Avalon Hill Game Company, 1983., D02340834O (Box BG 38)
    - Lords of Creation: The Yeti Sanction. Published by The Avalon Hill Game Company, 1984., D02340834O (Box BG 38)